Wayne on wheels!
McQ is a action, crime, drama film directed by John Sturges.
Police Lieutenant Lon McQ investigates the killing of his best friend and uncovers
corrupt elements of the police department dealing in confiscated drugs.
McQ, played by John Wayne.
Kosterman, played by Eddie Albert.
Lois, played by Diana Muldaur.
Myra, played by Colleen Dewhurst.
Toms, played by Clu Gulager.
Pinky, played by David Huddleston.
McQ is a 1974 American Panavision neo-noir crime action film
directed by John Sturges and starring John Wayne.
It costars Eddie Albert, Diana Muldaur, and Al Lettieri, and features Colleen Dewhurst, Clu
Gulager, David Huddleston, Julian Christopher (credited as Jim Watkins), Roger E.
Mosley, and William Bryant in supporting roles.
The film was shot in Washington, making extensive use of locations in Seattle and with a
sequence near the end filmed on the Pacific Coast in Moclips, Washington.
The tone is intense and emotional and mind_bending.